Finding Aid for Janice J. Terry papers, 1957-2007
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Janice J. Terry papers 1957-2007
Terry, Janice J.
1.5 linear feet
2008135 Aa 2
Janice J. Terry is a Middle East scholar and author, whose primary focuses are issues facing Palestine and Arab-Americans. The collection includes documents from Arab-American organizations, and publications detailing Palestine, Arab-Americans and the Middle East in General.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were donated to the library by Janice J. Terry, (donor no. 10022 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Janice Terry was born in 1942 in Cleveland, Ohio. She pursued her education at Wooster College, earning her Bachelors in 1964, later at the American University of Beirut, earning her masters in 1966, and finally at the University of London, earning her PhD in 1968. Throughout her career she has focused on modern Middle East history, particularly problems facing Palestine and Arab-Americans. She currently is emeritus professor of history at Eastern Michigan University in Ypsilanti, Michigan.
The collection dates from 1957 to 2007, and reflects Janice Terry's career interests, including documents relating to the Arab American Media Society, the Arab American National Museum, and other Arab-American organizations, as well as publications focusing on Palestine, Arab-Americans, and the Middle East in general. Additionally, the collection also includes audiotapes and videotapes.
Subjects:
Arab Americans--Michigan.; Terry, Janice J.
Genre Terms:
Oral histories.
- Arab American files, 1875-20007
  Arab American files (1975-2007, .5 linear feet) include documentation of the Arab American Media Society, the Arab American National Museum, Oral History projects, a Wayne State Teachers Conference, the Arab American Institute, and the National Association of Arab Americans. Of special note are the transcripts of interviews conducted with Arab American individuals in 1994 and 1996.
  - Arab American Media Society
    - Minutes, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Scripts (Box 1)
    - Middle East Trip, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Arab American National Museum, 2001-2006 (Box 1)
  - Museum Exhibits, 1982, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Oral History Interviews
    - Miscellaneous, 1985-1994 (Box 1)
    - Terry Ahwal, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Lila Howard, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Abdeen Jabara, 1994 (Box 1)
    - George Khoury, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Yahia Mawari, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Saleh Muslah, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Nabeel Abraham, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Ish Ahmed, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Ali Baleed, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Hasan Nawash, 1996 (Box 1)
      (includes audio cassette tape)
    - Margaret Sarafa, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Don Unis, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Wayne State Teachers Conference, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Arab-Americans, 1986-2006 (Box 1)
  - Arab American Institute, 1997-2004 (Box 1)
  - National Association of Arab Americans, 1980, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Middle Eastern Community Directory, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Mymonie Jabara, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1975-1997 (Box 1)
- Publications, 1857-2006
  Publications (1957-2006, .75 linear feet) include various American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee publications, assorted publications focusing on Palestine, and assorted publications focusing on the Middle East in General.
  - ADC
    - Reports, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
    - Times, 1986-2003 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Palestine Human Rights Bulletin/Newsletter, 1980-1989 (Box 1)
  - PLO Information Bulletin, 1975-1980 (Box 1)
  - Assorted Palestine Publications, 1969-1990 (Box 1)
  - The Middle East Newsletter, 1967-1971 (Box 1)
  - Arab Perspectives, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Middle East Forum, 1965-1972 (Box 2)
  - Conference on World Affairs Pamphlets, 1968-1973 (Box 2)
  - American Committee for Justice in the Middle East, Position Papers, 1969-1973 (Box 2)
  - Arab World Issues, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - Middle East Problem Papers, 1974 (Box 2)
  - ALECSO Papers, 1985 (Box 2)
  - National Lawyers Guild, 2001-2002 (Box 2)
  - FACTS, 1974 (Box 2)
  - SUASIA, 1977 (Box 2)
  - The Link, 1977-1988 (Box 2)
  - Resistance, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
  - Assorted Arab Culture and Music Pamphlets, 1976-2004 (Box 2)
  - Assorted Arab American Publications, 1980-2006 (Box 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1983-1997 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1957-1996 (Box 2)
- Audio-Visual Material, 1995-1996
  Audio Visual Materials (1995-1996, .25 linear feet) includes one audiocassette tape and two VHS tapes of a program called Tales from Arab Detroit.
  - Audio Cassette Tape, Sabreen (Middle Eastern Music) (Box 2)
  - Tales From Arab Detroit, 1995, 2 VHS tapes (Box 2)